air.bar 2018-09-09

# Privacy Policy

                               Storgatan 23c         info@neonode.com
                               SE-114 55 Stockholm   www.neonode.com
                                      Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy sets out how we, Neonode Technologies AB, collect, store and use information
about you when you use or interact with our website, www.air.bar (our website) and where we
otherwise obtain or collect information about you. This Privacy Policy is effective from May 08th, 2018.
Contents
Summary
Our details
Information we collect when you visit our website
Information we collect when you contact us
Information we collect when you interact with our website
Information we collect when you place an order on our website
Information collected or obtained from third parties
Our use of automated decision-making and profiling
Disclosure and additional uses of your information
How long we retain your information
How we secure your information
Transfers of your information outside the European Economic Area
Your rights in relation to your information
Your right to object to the processing of your information for certain purposes
Sensitive Personal Information
Changes to our Privacy Policy
Children’s Privacy
California Do Not Track Disclosures
Copyright, credit and logo
                                                                                                         UM

Summary
This section summarises how we obtain, store and use information about you. It is intended to provide
a very general overview only. It is not complete in and of itself and it must be read in conjunction
with the corresponding full sections of this Privacy Policy.
    •   Data controller: Neonode Technologies AB, Storgatan 23 C, SE-114 55, Stockholm, Sweden
    •   How we collect or obtain information about you:
             o     when you provide it to us (e.g. by contacting us, by placing an order on our website
                   and by signing up to our e-newsletter, by browsing our website,
             o     from your use of our website, using cookies and similar technologies, and
             o     occasionally, from third parties.
    •   Information we collect: name, contact details, payment information e.g. your credit or debit
        card details, IP address, information from cookies, information about your computer or device
        (e.g. device and browser type), information about how you use our website (e.g. which pages
        you have viewed, the time when you view them and what you clicked on, the geographical
        location from which you accessed our website (based on your IP address), company name or
        business name (if applicable), VAT number (if applicable).
    •   How we use your information: for administrative and business purposes (particularly to
        contact you and process orders you place on our website, to improve our business and website,
        to fulfil our contractual obligations, to advertise our goods and services, to analyse your use of
        our website, and in connection with our legal rights and obligations.
    •   Disclosure of your information to third parties: only to the extent necessary to run our
        business, to our service providers, to fulfil any contracts we enter into with you, where required
        by law or to enforce our legal rights.
    •   Do we sell your information to third parties (other than in the course of a business sale
        or purchase or similar event): No
    •   How long we retain your information: for no longer than necessary, taking into account any
        legal obligations we have (e.g. to maintain records for tax purposes), any other legal basis we
        have for using your information (e.g. your consent, performance of a contract with you or our
        legitimate interests as a business.
    •   How we secure your information: using appropriate technical and organisational measures
        such as storing your information on secure servers, encrypting transfers of data to or from our
        servers using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology, encrypting payments you make on or
                                                                                                         2
Privacy Policy - AirBar AM 1.5
                                                                                                       UM

         via our website using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology, only granting access to your
         information where necessary.
     •   Use of cookies and similar technologies: we use cookies and similar information-gathering
         technologies such as web beacons on our website including essential, functional, analytical
         and targeting cookies. For more information, please visit our cookies policy here:
         https://air.bar/misc/Cookies_Policy.pdf
     •   Transfers of your information outside the European Economic Area: in certain
         circumstances we transfer your information outside of the European Economic Area. Where
         we do so, we will ensure appropriate safeguards are in place, including the third parties we use
         who transfer your information outside the European Economic Area have self-certified
         themselves as compliant with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield.
     •   Use of automated decision making and profiling: we use automated decision making and/or
         profiling. We use web analytics, cookies, web beacons or server logs analysis tools for profiling
         and we use targeting cookies to display advertisements to people who visit our website on other
         websites around the internet (automated decision making).
     •   Your rights in relation to your information
              o   to access your information and to receive information about its use
              o   to have your information corrected and/or completed
              o   to have your information deleted
              o   to restrict the use of your information
              o   to receive your information in a portable format
              o   to object to the use of your information
              o   to withdraw your consent to the use of your information
              o   to complain to a supervisory authority
     •   Sensitive personal information: we do not knowingly or intentionally collect what is commonly
         referred to as ‘sensitive personal information’. Please do not submit sensitive personal
         information about you to us. For more information, please see the main section below entitled
         Sensitive Personal Information.
Our details
The data controller in respect of our website is Neonode Technologies AB (company registration
number: SE556771209501). You can contact the data controller by writing to Box 5082, SE-10242
Stockholm, Sweden or sending an email to hello@air.bar.
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact the data controller.
                                                                                                         3
Privacy Policy - AirBar AM 1.5
                                                                                                    UM

Information we collect when you visit our website
We collect and use information from website visitors in accordance with this section and the section
entitled Disclosure and additional uses of your information.
Web server log information
We use a third party server to host our website called Digital Ocean, the privacy policy of which is
available here: https://www.digitalocean.com/legal/privacy/ Our website server automatically logs the
IP address you use to access our website as well as other information about your visit such as the
pages accessed, information requested, the date and time of the request, the source of your access to
our website (e.g. the website or URL (link) which referred you to our website), and your browser version
and operating system. Our server is located in Germany.
Use of website server log information for IT security purposes
We and our third party hosting provider collect and store server logs to ensure network and IT security
and so that the server and website remain uncompromised. This includes analysing log files to help
identify and prevent unauthorised access to our network, the distribution of malicious code, denial of
services attacks and other cyber-attacks, by detecting unusual or suspicious activity.
Unless we are investigating suspicious or potential criminal activity, we do not make, nor do we allow
our hosting provider to make, any attempt to identify you from the information collected via server logs.
Legal basis for processing: compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject (Article
6(1)(c) of the General Data Protection Regulation).
Legal obligation: we have a legal obligation to implement appropriate technical and organisational
measures to ensure a level of security appropriate to the risk of our processing of information about
individuals. Recording access to our website using server log files is such a measure.
Legal basis for processing: our and a third party’s legitimate interests (Article 6(1)(f) of the General
Data Protection Regulation).
Legitimate interests: we and our third party hosting provider have a legitimate interest in using your
information for the purposes of ensuring network and information security.
Use of website server log information to analyse website use and improve our website
We use the information collected by our website server logs to analyse how our website users interact
with our website and its features. For example, we analyse the number of visits and unique visitors we
receive, the time and date of the visit, the location of the visit and the operating system and browser
used.
We use the information gathered from the analysis of this information to improve our website. For
example, we use the information gathered to change the information, content and structure of our
website and individual pages based according to what users are engaging most with and the duration
of time spent on particular pages on our website.
Legal basis for processing: our legitimate interests (Article 6(1)(f) of the General Data Protection
Regulation).
Legitimate interest: improving our website for our website users and getting to know our website
users’ preferences so our website can better meet their needs and desires.
                                                                                                         4
Privacy Policy - AirBar AM 1.5
                                                                                                    UM

Cookies and similar technologies
Cookies are data files which are sent from a website to a browser to record information about users for
various purposes.
We use cookies and similar technologies on our website, including essential, functional, analytical and
targeting cookies and web beacons. For further information on how we use cookies, please see our
cookies policy which is available here: https://air.bar/misc/Cookies_Policy.pdf
You can reject some or all of the cookies we use on or via our website by changing your browser
settings or non-essential cookies by not accepting the cookie consent pop-up, but doing so can impair
your ability to use our website or some or all of its features. For further information about cookies,
including how to change your browser settings, please visit www.allaboutcookies.org or see our cookies
policy.
Information we collect when you contact us
We collect and use information from individuals who contact us in accordance with this section and the
section entitled Disclosure and additional uses of your information.
Email
When you send an email to the email address displayed on our website we collect your email address
and any other information you provide in that email (such as your name, telephone number and the
information contained in any signature block in your email).
Legal basis for processing: our legitimate interests (Article 6(1)(f) of the General Data Protection
Regulation).
Legitimate interest(s): responding to enquiries and messages we receive and keeping records of
correspondence.
Legal basis for processing: necessary to perform a contract or to take steps at your request to enter
into a contract (Article 6(1)(b) of the General Data Protection Regulation).
Reason why necessary to perform a contract: where your message relates to us providing you
with goods or services or taking steps at your request prior to providing you with our goods and
services (for example, providing you with information about such goods and services), we will process
your information in order to do so).
Transfer and storage of your information
We use a third party email provider to store emails you send us. Our third party email provider is 24
Solutions. Their privacy policy is available here: https://www.24solutions.com/en/about-us/our-
policy/privacy-policy
Emails you send us will be stored within the European Economic Area on our third party email provider’s
servers in Sweden.
Contact form
When you contact us using our contact form or chat function, we collect your email address and IP
address. We also collect any other information you provide to us when you complete the contact form.
                                                                                                      5
Privacy Policy - AirBar AM 1.5
                                                                                                  UM

If you do not provide the mandatory information required by our contact form, you will not be able to
submit the contact form and we will not receive your enquiry.
Legal basis for processing: our legitimate interests (Article 6(1)(f) of the General Data Protection
Regulation).
Legitimate interest(s): responding to enquiries and messages we receive and keeping records of
correspondence.
Legal basis for processing: necessary to perform a contract or to take steps at your request to enter
into a contract (Article 6(1)(b) of the General Data Protection Regulation).
Reason why necessary to perform a contract: where your message relates to us providing you
with goods or services or taking steps at your request prior to providing you with our goods and
services (for example, providing you with information about such goods and services), we will process
your information in order to do so).
Transfer and storage of your information
Messages you send us via our contact form will be stored inside and outside the European Economic
Area on our third party provider’s servers. Our third party provider is Zendesk. Their privacy policy is
available here: https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/privacy-policy/
For further information about the safeguards used when your information is transferred outside the
European Economic Area, see the section of this privacy policy below entitled Transfers of your
information outside the European Economic Area.
We use a third party contact form provider to store messages you send us. Our contact form provider
is Zendesk. Their privacy policy is available here: https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-
partners/privacy-policy/ Messages you send to us via our contact form will be stored inside and outside
the European Economic Area on our contact form provider’s servers in EU, US and Japan.
For further information about the safeguards used when your information is transferred outside the
European Economic Area, see the section of this privacy policy below entitled Transfers of your
information outside the European Economic Area.
Phone
When you contact us by phone, we collect your phone number and any information provide to us during
your conversation with us.
We do not record phone calls.
Legal basis for processing: our legitimate interests (Article 6(1)(f) of the General Data Protection
Regulation)
Legitimate interest(s): responding to enquiries and messages we receive and keeping records of
correspondence.
Legal basis for processing: necessary to perform a contract or to take steps at your request to enter
into a contract (Article 6(1)(b) of the General Data Protection Regulation).
Reason why necessary to perform a contract: where your message relates to us providing you
with goods or services or taking steps at your request prior to providing you with our goods and
services (for example, providing you with information about such goods and services), we will process
your information in order to do so).
Transfer and storage of your information
Information about your call, such as your phone number and the date and time of your call, is processed
by our third party telephone service provider.
                                                                                                       6
Privacy Policy - AirBar AM 1.5
                                                                                                     UM

Post
If you contact us by post, we will collect any information you provide to us in any postal
communications you send us.
Legal basis for processing: our legitimate interests (Article 6(1)(f) of the General Data Protection
Regulation)
Legitimate interest(s): responding to enquiries and messages we receive and keeping records of
correspondence.
Legal basis for processing: necessary to perform a contract or to take steps at your request to enter
into a contract (Article 6(1)(b) of the General Data Protection Regulation).
Reason why necessary to perform a contract: where your message relates to us providing you
with goods or services or taking steps at your request prior to providing you with our goods and
services (for example, providing you with information about such goods and services), we will process
your information in order to do so).
Information we collect when you interact with our website
We collect and use information from individuals who interact with particular features of our website in
accordance with this section and the section entitled Disclosure and additional uses of your information.
E-Newsletter
When you sign up for our e-newsletter on our website or opt to receive news, offers, product and deal
announcements, information on firmware updates and other information related to our AirBar from us
by entering your name and email address and checking our Marketing permission “email”-box and
clicking subscribe to indicate you would like to receive our e-newsletter, we collect the information you
provide us and your IP address.
Legal basis for processing: your consent (Article 6(1)(a) of the General Data Protection Regulation).
Consent: you give your consent to us sending you our e-newsletter by signing up to receive it using
the steps described above.
Transfer and storage of your information
We use a third party service to send out our e-newsletter and administer our mailing list, MailChimp.
Their privacy policy is available here: https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/
Information you submit to subscribe for our e-newsletter will be stored outside the European Economic
Area on our third party mailing list provider’s servers in the United States For further information about
the safeguards used when your information is transferred outside the European Economic Area, see
the section of this privacy policy below entitled Transfers of your information outside the European
Economic Area.
Use of web beacons [and similar technologies] in emails
We use technologies such as web beacons (small graphic files) in the emails we send to allow us to
assess the level of engagement our emails receive by measuring information such as the delivery rates,
open rates and click through rates which our emails achieve.
For more information on how we use web beacons in our e-newsletter emails, see our cookies policy
which is available here: https://air.bar/misc/Cookies_Policy.pdf
                                                                                                         7
Privacy Policy - AirBar AM 1.5
                                                                                                           UM

For more information about our third party mailing list provider and how they use web beacons, please
see their privacy policy which is available here: https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/.
Information we collect when you place an order on our
website
We collect and use information from individuals who place an order on our website in accordance with
this section and the section entitled Disclosure and additional uses of your information.
Information collected when you place an order
Mandatory information
When you place an order for goods or services on our website, we collect your name, email address,
billing address, shipping address, company name (if applicable), VAT number (if applicable), and phone
number.
If you do not provide this information, you will not be able to purchase goods or services from us on our
website or enter into a contract with us.
We use a third party order processor for receiving and processing your order. Your order will be
processed by Centra. Centra collects, uses and processes your information in accordance with their
Data Processing Agreement.
Centra is located in Sweden. Information relating to the processing of your payment is stored within the
European Economic Area on our third party order processor’s server in the Netherlands and Ireland.
Legal basis for processing: necessary to perform a contract (Article 6(1)(b) of the General Data
Protection Regulation).
Reason why necessary to perform a contract: we need the mandatory information collected by our
checkout form to establish who the contract is with and to contact you to fulfil our obligations under
the contract, including sending you receipts and order confirmations.
Legal basis for processing: compliance with a legal obligation (Article 6(1)(c) of the General Data
Protection Regulation).
Legal obligation: we have a legal obligation to issue you with an invoice for the goods and services
you purchase from us where you are VAT registered and we require the mandatory information
collected by our checkout form for this purpose. We also have a legal obligation to keep accounting
records, including records of transactions.
Processing your payment
After you place an order on our website you will need to make payment for the goods or services you
have ordered. In order to process your payment, we use a third party payment processor. Your payment
will be processed by Adyen.
Adyen collects, uses and processes your information, including payment information, in accordance
with their privacy policies. You can access its privacy policy via the following link(s):
https://www.adyen.com/policies-and-disclaimer/privacy-policy .
                                                                                                        8
Privacy Policy - AirBar AM 1.5
                                                                                                       UM

Transfer and storage of your information
Adyen is located in the Netherlands. Information relating to the processing of your payment is stored
inside the European Economic Area on our third party payment processor’s servers in the European
Union.
For further information about the safeguards used when your information is transferred outside the
European Economic Area, see the section of this privacy policy below entitled Transfers of your
information outside the European Economic Area.
Legal basis for processing: necessary to perform a contract (Article 6(1)(b) of the General Data
Protection Regulation).
Reason why necessary to perform a contract: to fulfil your contractual obligation to pay for the
goods or services you have ordered from us.
Information collected or obtained from third parties
Where we receive information about you in error
If we receive information about you from a third party in error and/or we do not have a legal basis for
processing that information, we will delete your information to our best effort.
Our use of automated decision-making and profiling
We use automated decision making and profiling on our website. We do not consider that this has any
legal effect on you or similarly significantly affects you.
You have the right to object to our use of automated decision making and profiling described in this
section. You can do that by opting-out of cookies and similar technologies in accordance with the
method described in the relevant section below. If you do not want us to process your actual IP address
(usually the IP address assigned to you by your Internet Service Provider) when you visit our website,
you can use a Virtual Private Network (VPN) or a free service such as Tor.
You can find out more about our use of cookies and similar technologies (including the legal basis on
which we use them) and how to opt out from them in our cookies policy, which is available here:
https://air.bar/misc/Cookies_Policy.pdf
Automated decision making
Automated decision making is decision making by technological means (i.e. by a machine) without
human involvement.
Use of automated decision making for display advertising
We automate the display advertisements containing our products and services on other websites you
visit, you based on the fact that you have visited our website using cookies. For further information on
the cookies we use, please see our cookies policy which is available here:
https://air.bar/misc/Cookies_Policy.pdf
Logic involved: automatically displaying advertisements to individuals who have visited our website
results in increased efficiencies and costs savings for us than manually displaying advertisements or
displaying advertisements by different means.
                                                                                                        9
Privacy Policy - AirBar AM 1.5
                                                                                                          UM

Significance and envisaged consequences: cookies will be used to recognise the fact that you have
visited our website in order to display advertisements to you (unless you have blocked such cookies)
and will collect information about your online behaviour.
How to object: you can block these cookies by not accepting the cookie consent pop-up or by blocking
third party cookies using browser settings, or by opting out of seeing personalised ads from Google by
following the instructions here: https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en-GB] or by
opting out of seeing personalised ads from Facebook by following the instructions here:
https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217. For further information, please see our cookies
policy: https://air.bar/misc/Cookies_Policy.pdf
Profiling
Profiling is any form of automated processing of your information to evaluate personal aspects about
you, in particular to analyse or predict things like your performance at work, economic situation, health,
personal preferences, interests, reliability, behaviour, location or movements.
Use of profiling for web analytics
Our web analytics service, Google Analytics, uses and collects information such as your location (based
on your IP address) and your behaviour (based on cookies) when you access our website (such as the
pages you visit and what you click on). We will only process information from cookies if you have
consented to us setting cookies on your computer in accordance with our cookies policy:
https://air.bar/misc/Cookies_Policy.pdf
Logic involved: by automatically analysing and categorising information such as the location (based
on IP address) as well as the behaviour and devices of visitors to our website (using cookies), we are
able to gain a better understanding of what our website visitors want (in terms of the content of our
website and our products), how to improve our website and how to advertise and market our services
to them.
Significance and envisaged consequences: cookies will be used to track and store information about
your behaviour and device on our website unless you have opted out from receiving such cookies by
not accepting our cookies on first visit on a new device and your location will be analysed based on
your IP address. We may target advertisements based on the level of interest we receive from certain
visitors and their behaviour on our website.
Legal basis for processing: our legitimate interest from (Article 6(1)(f) of the General Data Protection
Regulation.
Legitimate interest: analysing the level of engagement and effectiveness of our website content in
order to improve our website and offering.
Use of profiling in marketing emails
We use web beacons and similar technologies in our marketing emails to analyse who opens our emails
and what actions they take (for example, what they click on). We will process information from web
beacons and similar technologies.
Logic involved: by analysing how our email recipients respond to our emails, we are able to improve
the content and effectiveness of our emails and gauge who is most interested.
                                                                                                       10
Privacy Policy - AirBar AM 1.5
                                                                                                         UM

Significance and envisaged consequences: your behaviour when you open our emails will be
tracked using small gif files (web beacons) including open rates and click through rates.
How to object: By emailing us at hello@air.bar asking for deletion of your data.
Legal basis for processing: legitimate interests (Article 6(1)(f) of the General Data Protection
Regulation).
Legitimate interest: analysing the level of engagement and effectiveness of our marketing emails and
content and improving our offering.
Disclosure and additional uses of your information
This section sets out the circumstances in which will disclose information about you to third parties and
any additional purposes for which we use your information.
Disclosure of your information to service providers
We use a number of third parties to provide us with services which are necessary to run our business
or to assist us with running our business and who process your information for us on our behalf. These
include the following:
     •    Email providers,
     •    IT service providers,
     •    Web developers,
     •    Hosting providers.
Our third party service providers are located inside and outside the European Economic Area (EEA).
Your information will be shared with these service providers where necessary to provide you with the
service you have requested, whether that is accessing our website or ordering goods and services from
us.
We do not display the identities of our service providers publicly by name for security and competitive
reasons. If you would like further information about the identities of our service providers, however,
please contact us directly by email at hello@air.bar and we will provide you with such information where
you have a legitimate reason for requesting it (where we have shared your information with such service
providers, for example.
Legal basis for processing: legitimate interests (Article 6(1)(f) of the General Data Protection
Regulation).
Legitimate interest relied on: where we share your information with these third parties in a context
other than where is necessary to perform a contract (or take steps at your request to do so), we will
share your information with such third parties in order to allow us to run and manage our business
efficiently.
Legal basis for processing: necessary to perform a contract and/or to take steps at your request
prior to entering into a contract (Article 6(1)(b) of the General Data Protection Regulation).
Reason why necessary to perform a contract: we may need to share information with our service
providers to enable us to perform our obligations under that contract or to take the steps you have
requested before we enter into a contract with you.
                                                                                                       11
Privacy Policy - AirBar AM 1.5
                                                                                                      UM

Disclosure of your information to other third parties
We disclose your information to other third parties in specific circumstances, as set out below.
Providing information to third parties such as Google Inc. and Facebook. Google collects
information through our use of Google Analytics on our website. Google uses this information, including
IP addresses and information from cookies, for a number of purposes, such as improving its Google
Analytics service. Information is shared with Google on an aggregated and anonymised basis. To find
out more about what information Google collects, how it uses this information and how to control the
information       sent       to      Google,        please        see       the      following      page:
https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/
Facebook Business services are used to gather data, analyse it and provide targeted advertising
messages. Facebook uses this information, including IP addresses and information from cookies, for a
number of purposes, such as improving its Facebook Business service.
Legal basis for processing: our legitimate interests (Article 6(1)(f) of the General Data Protection
Regulation).
Legitimate interest(s): meeting our contractual obligations to Google under our Google Analytics
Terms of Service https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html
You can opt out of Google Analytics                     by    installing  the   browser     plugin  here:
https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout
Transfer and storage of your information
Information collected by Google Analytics and Facebook is stored outside the European Economic Area
on Google’s and Facebook’s servers in the United States of America.
For further information about the safeguards used when your information is transferred outside the
European Economic Area, see the section of this privacy policy below entitled Transfers of your
information outside the European Economic Area.
Sharing your information with third parties, which are either related to or associated with the
running of our business, where it is necessary for us to do so. These third parties include our
accountants, advisors, affiliates, business partners, independent contractors, and insurers.
Legal basis for processing: our legitimate interests (Article 6(1)(f) of the General Data Protection
Regulation).
Legitimate interest: running and managing our business efficiently.
We do not display the identities of our third party providers publicly by name for security and
competitive reasons. If you would like further information about the identities of such third party
providers, however, please contact us directly by email at hello@air.bar and we will provide you with
such information where you have a legitimate reason for requesting it (where we have shared your
information with such service providers, for example.
Sharing your information with a prospective or actual purchaser or seller in the context of a
business or asset sale or acquisition by us, a merger or similar business combination event,
whether actual or potential.
Legal basis for processing: legitimate interests (Article 6(1)(f) of the General Data Protection
Regulation).
                                                                                                       12
Privacy Policy - AirBar AM 1.5
                                                                                                       UM

Legitimate interest(s): sharing your information with a prospective purchaser, seller or similar person
in order to allow such a transaction to take place.
Disclosure and use of your information for legal reasons
Indicating possible criminal acts or threats to public security to a competent authority
If we suspect that criminal or potential criminal conduct has been occurred, we will in certain
circumstances need to contact an appropriate authority, such as the police. This could be the case, for
instance, if we suspect that fraud or a cyber-crime has been committed or if we receive threats or
malicious communications towards us or third parties.
We will generally only need to process your information for this purpose if you were involved or affected
by such an incident in some way.
Legal basis for processing: our legitimate interests (Article 6(1)(f) of the General Data Protection
Regulation).
Legitimate interests: preventing crime or suspected criminal activity (such as fraud).
In connection with the enforcement or potential enforcement our legal rights
We will use your information in connection with the enforcement or potential enforcement of our legal
rights, including, for example, sharing information with debt collection agencies if you do not pay
amounts owed to us when you are contractually obliged to do so. Our legal rights may be contractual
(where we have entered into a contract with you) or non-contractual (such as legal rights that we have
under copyright law or tort law).
Legal basis for processing: our legitimate interests (Article 6(1)(f) of the General Data Protection
Regulation).
Legitimate interest: enforcing our legal rights and taking steps to enforce our legal rights.
In connection with a legal or potential legal dispute or proceedings
We may need to use your information if we are involved in a dispute with you or a third party for example,
either to resolve the dispute or as part of any mediation, arbitration or court resolution or similar process.
Legal basis for processing: our legitimate interests (Article 6(1)(f) of the General Data Protection
Regulation).
Legitimate interest(s): resolving disputes and potential disputes.
For ongoing compliance with laws, regulations and other legal requirements
We will use and process your information in order to comply with legal obligations to which we are
subject. For example, we may need to disclose your information pursuant to a court order or subpoena
if we receive one.
Legal basis for processing: compliance with a legal obligation (Article 6(1)(c) of the General Data
Protection Regulation).
Legal obligation(s): legal obligations to disclose information which are part of the laws of Sweden.
Legal basis for processing: our legitimate interests (Article 6(1)(f) of the General Data Protection
Regulation).
Legitimate interest: where the legal obligations are part of the laws of another country and have not
                                                                                                            13
Privacy Policy - AirBar AM 1.5
                                                                                                          UM

been integrated into the Sweden’s legal framework, we have a legitimate interest in complying with
these obligations.
How long we retain your information
This section sets out how long we retain your information. We have set out the criteria we use to
determine the retention period.
Retention periods
Order information: when you place an order for goods and services, we retain that information for seven
years following the end of the financial year in which you placed your order, in accordance with our
legal obligation to keep records for tax purposes.
Criteria for determining retention periods
In any other circumstances, we will retain your information for no longer than necessary, taking into
account the following:
    •   the purpose(s) and use of your information both now and in the future (such as whether it is
        necessary to continue to store that information in order to continue to perform our obligations
        under a contract with you or to contact you in the future);
    •   whether we have any legal obligation to continue to process your information (such as any
        record-keeping obligations imposed by relevant law or regulation);
    •   whether we have any legal basis to continue to process your information (such as your
        consent);
    •   how valuable your information is (both now and in the future);
    •   any relevant agreed industry practices on how long information should be retained;
    •   the levels of risk, cost and liability involved with us continuing to hold the information;
    •   how hard it is to ensure that the information can be kept up to date and accurate; and
    •   any relevant surrounding circumstances (such as the nature and status of our relationship with
        you).
How we secure your information
We take appropriate technical and organisational measures to secure your information and to protect it
against unauthorised or unlawful use and accidental loss or destruction, including:
    •   only sharing and providing access to your information to the minimum extent necessary, subject
        to confidentiality restrictions where appropriate, and on an anonymised basis wherever
        possible;
    •   using secure servers to store your information;
    •   verifying the identity of any individual who requests access to information prior to granting them
        access to information;
    •   using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software to encrypt any information you submit to us via any
        forms on our website and any payment transactions you make on or via our website;
                                                                                                         14
Privacy Policy - AirBar AM 1.5
                                                                                                           UM

     •     only transferring your information via closed system or encrypted data transfers.
Transmission of information to us by email
Transmission of information over the internet is not entirely secure, and if you submit any information
to us over the internet (whether by email, via our website or any other means), you do so entirely at
your own risk.
We cannot be responsible for any costs, expenses, loss of profits, harm to reputation, damages,
liabilities or any other form of loss or damage suffered by you as a result of your decision to transmit
information to us by such means.
Transfers of your information outside the European
Economic Area
Your data will be transferred or stored either within the European Economic Area or abroad. In the latter
case, your data is protected with the EU-US Privacy Shield as a safeguard. This applies to our following
third party providers: Google, Facebook, MailChimp and Zendesk.
EU-U.S. Privacy Shield is an approved certification mechanism under Article 42 of the General Data
Protection Regulation. This is permitted under Article 46(2)(f) of the General Data Protection
Regulation. You can access EU-U.S. Privacy Shield here: https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome and
the European Commission decision on the adequacy of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield here:
http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/international-transfers/adequacy/index_en.htm.
Your rights in relation to your information
Subject to certain limitations on certain rights, you have the following rights in relation to your
information, which you can exercise by writing to Neonode Technologies AB Box 5082, SE-102 42
Stockholm, Sweden or sending an email to hello@air.bar.
     •     to request access to your information and information related to our use and processing of
           your information;
     •     to request the correction or deletion of your information;
     •     to request that we restrict our use of your information;
     •     to receive information which you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used
           and machine-readable format (e.g. a CSV file) and the right to have that information
           transferred to another data controller (including a third party data controller);
     •     to object to the processing of your information for certain purposes (for further
           information, see the section below entitled Your right to object to the processing of your
           information for certain purposes); and
     •     to withdraw your consent to our use of your information at any time where we rely on your
           consent to use or process that information. Please note that if you withdraw your consent, this
           will not affect the lawfulness of our use and processing of your information on the basis of your
           consent before the point in time when you withdraw your consent.
                                                                                                          15
Privacy Policy - AirBar AM 1.5
                                                                                                           UM

In accordance with Article 77 of the General Data Protection Regulation, you also have the right to
lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the Member State of your habitual
residence, place of work or of an alleged infringement of the General Data Protection Regulation.
For the purposes of Sweden, the supervisory authority is the Datainspektionen (Swedish Data
Protection        Authority),      the    contact     details      of   which       are     available    here:
https://www.datainspektionen.se/in-english/contact-us/
Further information on your rights in relation to your personal data as an individual
You can find out further information about your rights, as well as information on any limitations which
apply to those rights, by reading the underlying legislation contained in Articles 12 to 22 and 34 of the
General Data Protection Regulation, which is available here: http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-
protection/reform/files/regulation_oj_en.pdf
Verifying your identity where you request access to your information
Where you request access to your information, we are required by law to use all reasonable measures
to verify your identity before doing so.
These measures are designed to protect your information and to reduce the risk of identity fraud, identity
theft or general unauthorised access to your information.
How we verify your identity
Where we possess appropriate information about you on file, we will attempt to verify your identity using
that information.
If it is not possible to identity you from such information, or if we have insufficient information about you,
we may require original or certified copies of certain documentation in order to be able to verify your
identity before we are able to provide you with access to your information.
We will be able to confirm the precise information we require to verify your identity in your specific
circumstances if and when you make such a request.
Your right to object to the processing of your information
for certain purposes
You have the following rights in relation to your information, which you may exercise in the same way
by writing to Neonode Technologies AB Box 5082, SE-102 42 Stockholm, Sweden or sending an email
to hello@air.bar:
       •   to object to us using or processing your information where we use or process it in order to carry
           out a task in the public interest or for our legitimate interests, including ‘profiling’ (i.e.
           analysing or predicting your behaviour based on your information) based on any of these
           purposes; and
       •   to object to us using or processing your information for direct marketing purposes (including
           any profiling we engage in that is related to such direct marketing).
You may also exercise your right to object to us using or processing your information for direct marketing
purposes by:
        •   clicking the unsubscribe link contained at the bottom of any marketing email we send to you
            and following the instructions which appear in your browser following your clicking on that link.
                                                                                                            16
Privacy Policy - AirBar AM 1.5
                                                                                                           UM

For more information on how to object to our use of information collected from cookies and similar
technologies, please see the section entitled How to accept or reject cookies in our cookies policy,
which is available here: https://air.bar/misc/Cookies_Policy.pdf
Sensitive Personal Information
‘Sensitive personal information’ is information about an individual that reveals their racial or ethnic
origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership, genetic
information, biometric information for the purpose of uniquely identifying an individual, information
concerning health or information concerning a natural person’s sex life or sexual orientation.
We do not knowingly or intentionally collect sensitive personal information from individuals, and you
must not submit sensitive personal information to us.
If, however, you inadvertently or intentionally transmit sensitive personal information to us, you will be
considered to have explicitly consented to us processing that sensitive personal information under
Article 9(2)(a) of the General Data Protection Regulation. We will use and process your sensitive
personal information for the purposes of deleting it.
Changes to our Privacy Policy
We update and amend our Privacy Policy from time to time.
Minor changes to our Privacy Policy
Where we make minor changes to our Privacy Policy, we will update our Privacy Policy with a new
effective date stated at the beginning of it. Our processing of your information will be governed by the
practices set out in that new version of the Privacy Policy from its effective date onwards.
Major changes to our Privacy Policy or the purposes for which we process your information
Where we make major changes to our Privacy Policy or intend to use your information for a new purpose
or a different purpose than the purposes for which we originally collected it, we will notify you by email
(where possible) or by posting a notice on our website.
We will provide you with the information about the change in question and the purpose and any other
relevant information before we use your information for that new purpose.
Wherever required, we will obtain your prior consent before using your information for a purpose that is
different from the purposes for which we originally collected it.
Children’s Privacy
Because we care about the safety and privacy of children online, we comply with the Children’s Online
Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA). COPPA and its accompanying regulations protect the privacy
of children using the internet. We do not knowingly contact or collect information from persons under
the age of 18. The website is not intended to solicit information of any kind from persons under the age
of 18.
It is possible that we could receive information pertaining to persons under the age of 18 by the fraud
or deception of a third party. If we are notified of this, as soon as we verify the information, we will,
where required by law to do so, immediately obtain the appropriate parental consent to use that
information or, if we are unable to obtain such parental consent, we will delete the information from our
                                                                                                        17
Privacy Policy - AirBar AM 1.5
                                                                                                           UM

servers. If you would like to notify us of our receipt of information about persons under the age of 18,
please do so by sending an email to hello@air.bar.
California Do Not Track Disclosures
“Do Not Track” is a privacy preference that users can set in their web browsers. When a user turns on
a Do Not Track signal in their browser, the browser sends a message to websites requesting that they
do not track the user. For information about Do Not Track, please visit www.allaboutdnt.org
Some internet browsers have incorporated “Do Not Track” (DNT) technologies that can send a signal
to the websites that you visit indicating you do not wish to be tracked. We do not currently respond to
browser DNT signals.
Copyright, credit and logo
This Privacy Policy is based on a General Data Protection Regulation (Regulation (EU) 2016/769)
(GDPR) compliant template provided by GDPR Privacy Policy. For further information, please visit
https://gdprprivacypolicy.org
The copyright in this Privacy Policy is either owned by, or licensed to, us and is protected by copyright
laws around the world and copyright protection software. All intellectual property rights in this document
are reserved.
Where we display the GDPR Privacy Policy logo on our website, this is used to indicate that we have
adopted a privacy policy template provided by GDPR Privacy Policy as the basis for this Privacy Policy.
Ulf Mårtensson
VP Operations
                                                                                                        18
Privacy Policy - AirBar AM 1.5
